Andy Principe

Web Developer - New York City





andyprincipe@gmail.com Summary

andyprincipe.com

804.873.8723

Languages

JavaScript

Ruby

Frameworks

Backbone

Polymer

Node w/ Express

Rails

Sinatra

Testing

Jasmine

RSpec

HTML & CSS

SCSS & Less

Responsive

Modernizr

CSS frameworks

Tools

git

npm

heroku

Grunt & Gulp

Agile

Scrum

On the Web:



I am an ambitious problem solver with a passion for learning and have proven experience delivering creative and well built solutions. With an interest in design and user experience, I am a constructive member of any team, providing insight to all parts of the software development lifecycle. I take responsibility and pride in my personal development, continually sharpening my skills so that I can remain current on the latest practices and technologies.

Experience

VSA Partners, Developer

March 2015 - Present

- Creates and implements new features for IBM's internal intranet, YourIBM, collaborating with other internal IBM teams and integration partners
- Practices test driven development, authors thorough documentation and engages in peer code review process to ensure quality of code
- Led the development effort on IBM's 2014 Corporate Responsibility Report, www.ibm.com/ibm/responsibility/2014, and IBM's Global Financing (IGF) site, www.ibm.com/financing/us-en/
- Executes designs and UX wireframes into highly stylized and interactive corporate blogposts and email campaigns

Cobalt, Technical Project Manager

March 2012 - May 2014

- Managed the on-going development effort for Cobalt's RAMCO (Realtor Association Management Co-Op) product
- Triaged bugs, wrote feature specifications, oversaw development, deployed code updates, quality assurance testing, and rolled out all hot fixes and new code versions to client Realtor associations
- Converted and imported legacy client data into SQL Server Management Studio, then appropriately mapped data and customized target CRM organizations with all necessary custom attributes and entities before converting data into RAMCO product

Freelance Web Developer

June 2014 - Present

Various web development projects

Education

The College of William and Mary - Williamsburg, VA

B.A. Music, American Studies

Dev Bootcamp - Chicago, IL



